SR. SOFTWARE QA ENGINEER

Summary

Software quality assurance is an art of ensuring software products are reliable and functionalities precisely matched with the specifications. With your knowledge, skills and experiences you help set up scenarios matching with the ways customers are using the products and rigorously ensure that defects are found and resolved before the products released to the customers. Customers gain trust and confidence in the products because of your works.

More than A fifteen years of experience in various areas of IT and software, including database, networking, operating systems, storage, system integration, software architect, design and development, software testing and automation, coupled with my work ethics help me to serve and contribute as a senior software quality assurance engineer in a growing company.

Skills

- Software quality assurance
- Technical trouble shooting
- Operating systems
- Software development
- Leadership
- Communication
- Mentoring
- Efficient time management

Experience

Amazon Lab126 Cambridge, MA Sr. Software QA Engineer 12/2015 to Current

- Ensure the highest quality of the ArcSight ESM Manager product released to the market.
- Create test plans, test cases, testing strategy.
- Triage feature requests and bug fixes with Product Management and Development.
- Reproduce the issues and scenarios.
- Test and verify fixes.
- Ensure no regressions.
- Produce products release notes and installation guides.
- Automate testing using Java, Selenium Web Driver, TestNG, and Jenkins.
- Perform product performance testing and analysis.
- Provide product insights and team leadership.

â€∢

Crane Co. Marion, NC Sr. Technical Software Support Engineer - Level 3 10/2009 to 12/2015

- Provided technical leadership for supporting ArcSight ESM Manager
- Investigated technical issues.
- Reviewed tickets and provided technical guidance to team members.
- Handled escalations.
- Interacted with customers on the phone, online or via emails.
- Acted as a liaison to internal development groups.
- Traveled to customer sites to assist trouble-shooting and providing solutions to customers' hot issues.
- Provided internal trainings to members of the groups.
- Wrote and reviewed knowledge- based articles.
- Presented performance tuning guidelines to nationwide ArcSight User Conferences.

â€∢

Gigya Oak Brook, IL Level 2/3 Escation Technical Support 11/2006 to 05/2009

- Provided level 2/3 technical support for FLEXNet Manager software, a J2EE enterprise licensing software SDK; handled escalation; wrote knowledge base articles; worked and resolved customers incidents; attended triage meetings with engineers and managers; mentored and provided technical leadership to junior members of the team.
- Skills: Customer service, people skills, Linux/Unix, windows, database, network, J2EE, Java, C/C++, trouble- shooting, multi-tasking, mentoring, escalation.

ŝ€.

Hewlett Packard City, STATE Application Specialist 03/2003 to 11/2006

- Provided level 3 escalation support for the HP Service Bus, an internal A2A application running on Oracle database and based on Weblogic.
- Skills: EDI, trouble-shooting, customer service, Oracle, MySQL, Weblogic, network, multi-tasking.

â€∢

Worldcom/MCI City, STATE Senior Software Engineer 12/2000 to 07/2002

- Designed an VOIP product using IETF SIP technical specification.
- Provided the detail design, data flows and specification of the product to engineering.
- Participated in the IETF SIP forum to provide feedbacks and raised questions.
- Tested and supported the proof of concept of the product.
- Skills: software development, technical writing, SIP, VOIP, testing, technical support.

Excel Telecommunications City, STATE Enterprise Information Technology Architect 11/1998 to 11/2000

- Participated in the design of a new EDI solution to support selling of local telephone services.
- Participated in the design and implemented of the EDI solution.
- Provided general directions, technical guidance and directions for the company.
- Skills: architect, operating systems, databases, network, proof of concepts, testing, lab.

â€∢

Electronic Data Systems City, STATE Advanced Software Systems Engineer 11/1985 to 11/1998

- Worked as an application programmer for the internal payroll system using Cobol, CICS, ALC; worked as a system programmer to install
 and integrate new versions of OS, database applications, network applications; developed utilities for system automation; provided QA
 scripts to test the quality of the whole software distribution package; provided technical support and direction to data centers.
- Worked as a system admin and database administration for Unix, Windows; acted as a point of contact for various customer accounts.
- Skills: software development, system engineering, systems management, customer support, COBOL, ALC, CICS, MVS, VM, VTAM,
 Netview, Rexx, Unix, Windows, network admin, Oracle, hardware, storage, system applications, software utilities, Windows NT 4 MCSE
 certification, integration, automation, QA, process re-engineer, onsite consulting.

â€∢

Education and Training

Master of Science: Computer Networking 1998 The University of Texas at Dallas, City, State, USA Master of Science: Computer Networking The University of Texas at Dallas, City, State, USA

Associate of Applied Science: Application Programming 1983 Portland Community College, City, State, USA

1988 EDS Systems Engineering Development 1992 EDS System Programmer Development

Skills

Architect, automation, Java, C, CICS, COBOL, shell scripting, EDI, J2EE, hardware, consulting, technical support, database applications, Oracle, MySQL, Linux, Windows, network admin, quality, QA, shell scripting, software development, specification, strategy, system engineering, systems management, technical writing, triage, trouble-shooting, multi-tasking, people skills, team leadership, mentoring, planning. Activities and Honors

1980 - 1983: Presidential and Dean Lists